SYED HASNAIN BUKHARI Profile-pio



FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUT

LIFE SUKHUMVIT 48, FLOOR 24TH, 122 SUKHUMVIT RD, PHRA KHANONG BANGKOK KHLONG TOEI 10110

SYEDHASNAINBUKHARI01@H OTMAIL.COM

(+66) 630789575. (+92) 3017924305

WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/HAS NAIN-BUKHARI-30494184 🗗

IN/HASNAIN BUKHARI 🗗

HASNAIN BUKHARI 🗗

WEB ENGINEERING

EXPERT

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE **DEVELOPMENT AND** TROUBLESHOOTING PROJECT MANAGEMENT & COORDINATION

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE

ADVANCED

DESIGN-PATTERNS DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS SCALABILITY MAINTAINABILITY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

PROFICIENT

SUSTAINABILITY **PORTABILITY SCALABILITY** REASONABILITY

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

ADVANCED

C#

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with 5+ years of rich professional experience of building and delivering highly scalable, enterprise grade software products. I hold a Bachelor's degree in Computer Sciences from the Punjab University College of Information Technology, Lahore, Pakistan

EXPERIENCE

AGODA

12/2021 - PRESENT

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Leading several teams, working on solutions based upon distributed computing to make the e-commerce scene under the global travel space alive

- Working with teams to migrate long-running legacy systems to a newer and
- Keeping track of the learning abilities of my team so that they can progress in their respective careers and interests
- Having 1:1s to shape up the team culture and align them with essential matters at the organization
- Build a mindset and culture of quality first; Owning our stuff and converting them to quality artefacts and systems
- Help the organization envision what moving away from legacy could mean and preach the benefits within the team(s)
- Help the team understand Agility at work and take them through ceremonies; This helps the team give their best following sprints
- Making an effort around organizational values, so it lives within the team and work we do.

STRATEGIC SYSTEM INTERNATIONAL

11/2019 - 12/2021

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Design and developed multiple major modules and provide technical support to web application as well mobile application. My responsibilities include:

- Building micro services oriented systems that enable integration with various external systems.
- Working in an agile, scrum environment using .NET stack to design and build highly optimized solutions to be deployed at a global scale.
- Optimizing and refactoring existing modules to accommodate new functionality and enhance performance and maintainability.
- Design and develop timesheets management module based on types of systems. User can track workings hours and working experience with different clients. User can upload paper timesheets as well.
- Implementation of Elastic search to enhance the performance and visualize
- Provide technical to mobile application
- Provide technical support and consultancy to other projects as well

CUREMD

09/2017 - 11/2019

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Developed multiple major projects, as a full stack .NET developer as well as a software architect. My responsibilities include:

- Building highly scalable and robust, service-oriented systems that enable integration of our flagship product with various external information
- Working in an agile, scrum environment using .NET stack to design and build highly optimized solutions to be deployed at a global scale.
- Providing technical and client support to various deployed products. Coordinate and plan inter and intra team activities.
- Restructure and refactor modules of existing products to accommodate new functionality and enhance performance and maintainability.

LOGIX INFINITY

06/2016 - 09/2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Worked as a software developer, specializing in web and desktop application development, mainly using the .NET stack along with other web technologies

WEB PROGRAMMING

PROFICIENT

ASP.NET
(WEB FORM, MVC, .NET CORE, NHIBERNATE, ENTITY
FRAMEWORK, ADO.NET, WEB API, WCF AND WPF),
MICRO SERVICES
ELASTIC SEARCH
JAVASCRIPT/JQUERY,

HTML/CSS

REPORTS

COMPETENT

CRYSTAL REPORTS
JSREPORTS

REPORTS

COMPETENT

MS SQL POSTGRESQL SQLLITE MONGODB

LANGUAGES

URDU (NATIVE SPEAKER) ENGLISH (FLUENT) ENGLISH (FLUENT) PUNJABI (FLUENT)

INTERESTS

HOME IMPROVEMENTS & ENGINEERING

Plumbing
Electric-appliances
Civil engineering

SOFTWARE BASED HOME SOLUTIONS

IoT Home-server plex raspberry-pi cups saned

WATCHING DOCUMENTARIES

Idiocracy Lord-of-the-rings movies documentaries (Angular, Ionic and JavaScript). It gave me a chance to work on an array of diverse projects, offering me a great learning experience and exposure. I've developed web-based software using ASP.NET (MVC, WEB API, .NetCore), Angular/Ionic and SQLServer.

EDUCATION

FAST - NUCES

BACHELOR COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Digital Logic Design
- Assembly Language
- Data Structures
- · Design Patterns
- · Web Programming

- Compiler Construction
- Concurrent and Distributed Systems

06/2006 - 07/2010

- High Performance Computing
- Database Design

AWARDS

IASA IT ARCHITECTURE CORE (ITAC) - CITAF CERTIFICATION

IASA GLOBAL

Anchors to the beginning of Architect position and responsibilities

WON THE GIKI SOFTCOM 08 (PROGRAMMING COMPETITION)

GIKI UNIVERSITY PAKISTAN

A speed programming competition of national level

REFERENCES

Amir is surely missed by his team/peers and I think any company would find great benefit with the addition of Amir to their leadership and technical team. Wish you all the best Amir and hope our paths cross again.

- HEINRICH RUST

As a colleague Amir is friendly, personable, has an easy manner and great sense of humour. A clear communicator with a voice for radio, Amir is wise head on young shoulders.

- PAUL FITZGERALD